Art + Politics = Power
Max is a war, drama film directed by Menno Meyjes.
In 1918, a young, disillusioned Adolf Hitler strikes up a friendship with a
Jewish art dealer while weighing a life of passion for art vs.
talent at politics
Max Rothman, played by John Cusack.
Adolf Hitler, played by Noah Taylor.
Liselore von Peltz, played by Leelee Sobieski.
Nina Rothman, played by Molly Parker.
George Grosz, played by Kevin McKidd.
Hildegard, played by Yuliya Vysotskaya.
Max is a 2002 drama film written and directed by
Menno Meyjes in his directorial debut.
The film stars John Cusack, Noah Taylor, Leelee Sobieski, and Molly Parker.
Its plot depicts a fictional friendship between Jewish art dealer Max Rothman and a young Austrian painter, Adolf Hitler; more of which explores
Hitler's views that begin to take shape as the Nazi ideology while also studying the artistic and design implications of the Third Reich.
It goes on to study the question of what could have been
had Hitler been accepted as an artist.
The tone is emotional.